hi sterling Allen here at we're at the
Tesla tech conference 2011 in
Albuquerque New Mexico July 29th and I'm
with Vernon Roth here this is actually
the second part of a two-part a video
series the first part we'll have a link
there in the bottom in this YouTube
video where you can see where he
described this chemical process where in
his electrolysis scenario he's found
that some of the elements that are in
the water in certain electrolysis
scenarios are duplicated whether they're
minerals or whether they are chemicals
chemical compounds and the question I
didn't ask him was
what about molecules like insulin for
example could you
he found that elements that are within
the water are duplicated so that he
started with one part in some cases he
saw with the cycling of the water they
actually had 13 times as much of that
element at the end than they had at the
beginning and this is true with gold
particles and with some fairly complex
chemical compounds that he that's right
that's in part a we went through all
that kind of the philosophy behind it
and the part this video here is to
describe the apparatus he's actually
agreed to go ahead and take things apart
and show us exactly how he makes that's
not exactly I mean this is going to be
fairly technical but you know it's not
like he's going to show you you know a
to Z but he is going to give us a good
overview going through each component
and now that I given that explanation I
would like to go ahead and turn it over
I'm going to go ahead and
control the camera but I'd like vermin
to recap what I just said in his words
to begin with and then we'll we'll make
this cut this video into what however
segments we need to as Part B of this
series all right let's go for it
well thank you sir Liam thank you for
everybody for being here and we're going
to move on forward so I think that one
of the most important things that we can
you know that we can do with our energy
and for the future is to find out more
and better ways to use water in our
world that's really a huge portion of my
research as many of you experienced the
spark of life water and its various
incarnations and what that what it's
used for that's really my driving focus
the forces to find out different ways to
use water in the world and so that's
what I do with hydrogen and then make
hydrogen and oxygen from from
electricity and water so that's what
we're talking about here and this is a
basic cell this is what we call it dry
cell before you get into them yeah this
is actually take two the first thing we
thought the camera was rolling in it
wasn't
tell us about what happened with after
you gave your presentation two people
came up to you Oh yesterday after I gave
my presentation to people independently
came up to me and said we also have
experienced the multiplication of
elements that we did not expect at all
using energy magnetic fields and
geometrical structures and occurring on
a much on a much smaller scale than what
we're experiencing here but it is
occurring and so they said we were so
glad that that someone else talked about
it because now we know that we're not
crazy now that we
we know that this is actually reality so
it's very exciting stuff and this is
going to I feel like it's going to be
happening more and more and many people
may already actually be doing it and not
knowing what's going on so with that
said we will start with we'll start with
hydrogen while we start where I started
and what we have over here is a
conventional well it uses some
principles above voices work with
hydrogen uses some principles of George
Wiseman and Uwe Browns work with
hydrogen the simple hydrogen cell with
parallel stainless steel plates in it
you input 120 volts DC and this it's not
supposed to be in there and the gas
comes out of the hydrogen unit goes into
the reservoir which acts like a trap and
an expansion chamber to trap vapors and
then the gas feeds from the reservoir
into a first stage bubbler which is this
is a safety bubbler and it and it also
serves as a a wash for the gas to wash
off any sodium hydroxide and then the
gas escapes out the top and this little
hose you see down at the bottom is the
water feed to the hydrogen device so gas
a little bit of water comes out here and
the water returns to the bottom and then
fills the device this is a small device
that well not not a not a very small
device but it's a it's a simple device
excuse me and this was commissioned by a
friend of mine to run a to help run his
diesel generator on his his mountain
retreat and it uses the solar panels a
set of solar panels about about a
thousand watts of solar panel goes into
this and boosts his hydrogen our suit
boost is a diesel engine once it leaves
that just just on a tangent what kind of
improvements does he see on the diesel
generator using that well what we
calculated was that
because there is no parasitic drag from
an alternator to feed his to feed his
engine using this and one other piece of
technology that's not mine so I can't
talk about it but it's a passive device
he we calculated that he will get about
a 90 percent boost in his diesel
generator system so that's almost a
double of his absolutely and then that's
taken into account the wattage from the
solar panel yes that take it's like a
voltage multiplier we're using you're
using water instead of and we're using
water and hydrogen that is not what
you're going to get if you have a
parasitic dragon you're running it off
your own generator that's just what the
solar panels but he found that it was
cheaper for him to do that and use a
generator as his existing power source
than it was to it to install a big solar
system with batteries and all the
electrical components would go along
with that this is more plug-and-play for
Hammond II and he likes that so this one
is built for with 1,000 watt solar
panels he was able to power his house
1000 watts and a diesel generator in a
diesel generator generator right so he's
running his house on the diesel
generator with a 1,000 watt solar panel
right essentially okay and 9 and 10
percent is this augmenting so he had
he's also plugged into the grid or is he
off grid he will be off grid once he
goes this way because his electricity
will be cheaper with this method than it
will be off of the conventional grid
system so this is also what I brought to
show a simple system the most simple
system that you can that you can deal
that you can create hydrogen device
reservoir bubbler and this is very safe
and it's easy to me and it's got a lot
of safeties built in especially at the
end when the water or when the hydrogen
comes out of there and goes into here
this is our flashback arrestor and the
last line of defense for this system
which it's filled with water and it
bubbles through it and then the gas goes
so generally
if we were running a torch we were going
to run a torch safer welding of in a
welding shop one more system would be
installed here and that is this
flashback arrestor and this is something
off the shelf this is something off the
shelf you buy them for forty to sixty
dollars a pair you get it at any welding
shop I recommend I highly recommend it
and it's called a flashback is called a
flashback or a spark back arrestor they
use them for oxygen and acetylene
torches as well as hydrogen torches as
well I recommend on this system down
here using any kind of conditioning of
the DC that's coming into it are using
it no we're not it's straight line DC
and I went with I went with straight
line DC because it's easier to work with
the only current control that I that I
put in the system is the number of
plates and the concentration of catalyst
when I start working with this I started
working with electronic gizmos and the
and the pulse width modulator and all
that burned him up pretty quick and in
my experimental phase realized I wanted
something a little more foolproof and so
I developed a way of calculating number
of plates to the current ratios that I
wanted and also the catalyst the amount
of catalyst in the system could help
control the current flow did we go over
those numbers this morning we have not
yet and so I was gonna I was going to
outline that guys I can illustrate it
very easily praise
but essentially I'll just give you the
numbers right now maximum two point two
three volts per cell maximum one quarter
watt there's even one quarter amp per
square inch of plate surface so for
instance we have a 6 by 6 plate here so
that's 36 square inches and if we were
using this the 6x6
not including the ring in here just
ignore
if we were using the 6 by 6 plate
putting current across that our limit
would be 9 amps because 9 divided by 36
is of course 4 so that's our 1/4 and per
square inch that's a maximum amount I
actually like to run about about using
that plate I'd like to learn about 5
amps just to make certain that there's a
nice nice margin of safety there so
whether you had 2 plates or a hundred
plates you go based on one surface
you're not going to exceed this cell
system that's right by 5 amp and by 9
amps that's right exactly
now this system you know we'll get into
that so we've got if we were using these
plates we would go 9 amps since the
since we've actually cut off surface
area in this device I go less than 9
amps and then we go to 2.3 5 volts or
2.3 4 volts per cell so there's no
longer than 2 points no more because
you'll start to burn up your place okay
so there's one two three four five six
cells in there so you would not go more
than 14 volts before the lay person I'm
seeing you at 24 so this isn't this is a
double unit okay there's a there's a
negative plate in the center and a
positive plate on one side on a positive
plate on the other so what you're
actually seeing is two two sets of
hydrogen that a two stacked hydrogen
device and so going from this side to
this side what are you calling a cell
the cell is the different distance
between plates so there's one two three
four five six cells in there and then we
go to the other side
one two three four oh I'm sorry there's
no there's six the other six okay six so
there's six on each side with it with an
with a negative center so there's a
positive and a negative positive on the
other side set to positive negative
twelve piece of metal makes a 6-cell
plate yeah and this this appears to be
the conventional cell that you can buy
on almost any hydrogen cell device but
it's not and we'll get into the
difference but we have we have two
inputs fuel in our Sumeet water in
hydrogen out say what yeah there's 13
plates there well 13 pieces of metal
yeah 13 pieces of metal negative in the
center and you can see I slip on a
little super neutral negative you call
it new neutral neutral are the ones in
between the negative and the positive
okay you just put on a little Spade
connector on the bottom slip it on and
and then the positive go up there a
little Spade connector on the edges I
sell this for about four three hundred
bucks
this is actually my breather unit I used
this to breathe Browns gas but we'll get
into that as we as we move forward so
that is the essential that is
essentially what we're dealing with here
only that one it's a larger scale so
there's there's sixty plates in that
device with a nice nice little water
jacket on either side to make certain
things stay cool and 60 plates takes 120
volts so that's 2 volts per cell so or
you know there abouts
and on that one we're dealing with a
little bit larger larger plates so I can
actually go up to 12 amps per per per 12
pounds for the whole unit because the
plates are actually larger so for the
voltage it's additive for the number of
cells right and four amp it's it's based
on the surface of one a single of cells
right we start with max we're in a
series
system so it's the it's the the amperage
is based off of one plate versus the
voltage being based off of the entire
set of plates okay so that's a little
bit of the technicalities that we we go
into with this with this type of
hydrogen device and these are these are
rules that have been tried out many
tried and proven many times if you go
over amperage you'll start to
crystallize your plates and they won't
produce gas very well if you go over
voltage just start to break down your
you'll just start to break down your
plates and let me add rules or whether
they are chemicals chemical compounds
and the question I didn't ask him ways
what about molecules like insulin for
example could you he founded elements
that are within the water are duplicated
so that if he started with one part in
some cases he saw with the cycling of
the water they actually had thirteen
times as much of that element at the end
than they had at the beginning and this
is true with gold particles and with
some fairly complex chemical compounds
said he that's right that's in Part A we
went through all that kind of the
philosophy behind it and the part this
video here is to describe the apparatus
he's actually agreed to go ahead and
take things apart and show us exactly
how he makes that's not exactly I mean
this is going to be fairly technical but
you know it's not like he's going to
show you you know a to Z but he is going
to give us a good overview going through
each component and now that I given that
explanation I would i sterling Allen
here I we're at the Tesla tech
conference 2011 you know
New Mexico July 29th and I'm with Verna
Roth here this is actually the second
part of a two-part a video series the
first part will have link there in the
bottom in this YouTube video where you
can see where he described this chemical
process where in his electrolysis
scenario he's found that some of the
elements that are in the water in
certain electrolysis scenarios are
duplicated whether they're armed in
future is to find out more and better
ways to use water in our world that's
really a huge portion of my research as
many of you experienced the spark of
life water and its various incarnations
and what that what it's used for that's
really my driving forces to find out
different ways to use water in the world
and so that's what I do with hydrogen
and then make hydrogen and oxygen from
from electricity and water so that's
what we're talking about here and this
is a basic cell this is what we call it
dry sunlight to go ahead and turn it
over I'm going to go ahead and control
the camera but I'd like Vernon to recap
what I just said in his words to begin
with and then we'll we'll make this cut
this video into what however segments we
need to as Part B of this series all
right let's go for it
well thank you sterling and thank you
for everybody for being here and we're
going to move on forward so I think that
one of the most important things that we
can you know that we can do with our
energy and for the